<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/episodes/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-31T22:06:44-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/episodes/atom.xml</id><title type="html">The Government We Need</title><subtitle>A podcast exploring the government of the future and how it can best serve everyone.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How government can design a human-centered social safety net</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-design-a-human-centered-social-safety-net" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How government can design a human-centered social safety net" /><published>2021-01-31T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-31T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-design-a-human-centered-social-safety-net</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-design-a-human-centered-social-safety-net">&lt;p&gt;For those in need of social services – unemployment, housing, healthcare, food – the safety net isn’t easy to navigate or access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the COVID crisis has exacerbated this reality. There has been a dramatic spike in benefits claims, especially in communities of color and those that were already teetering on the edge. This pandemic has spotlighted the extreme inequities of the haves and have-nots, and the very broken social safety net meant to provide benefits and assistance to people in need, particularly when disaster strikes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode, we talk with &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeforamerica.org&quot;&gt;Code for America&lt;/a&gt; Executive Director Amanda Renteria. Code for America’s mission is to build “a 21st century government that effectively and equitably serves all Americans.” As part of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/safetynetblueprint/about/&quot;&gt;Social Safety Net Portfolio&lt;/a&gt;, CfA has produced a ‘Blueprint for a Human-Centered Safety Net’ aimed at “transforming the delivery of public benefits in the digital age.” It also manages digital social service tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/programs/getcalfresh&quot;&gt;GetCalFresh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/programs/clear-my-record&quot;&gt;ClearMyRecord&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/programs/clientcomm&quot;&gt;ClientComm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/programs/getyourrefund&quot;&gt;GetYourRefund&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Code for America says of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/programs/integrated-benefits&quot;&gt;Integrated Benefits Initiative&lt;/a&gt;, “In the United States, the social safety net is composed of more than 80 services that together aim to lift almost 50 million Americans above the poverty line each year. Today, tens of millions of those people are still falling through the cracks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda talks with &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegovweneed.com/&quot;&gt;The Government We Need&lt;/a&gt; about how government can build a more responsive and dignified social safety net to support those who need it most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;related&quot;&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/safetynetblueprint/&quot;&gt;Blueprint for a Human-Centered Safety Net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeforamerica.org/programs/integrated-benefits&quot;&gt;Integrated Benefits Initiative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/90479768/how-to-redesign-americas-safety-net&quot;&gt;How to redesign America’s safety net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gcn.com/articles/2018/09/04/cfa-integrated-benefits-initiative.aspx&quot;&gt;Redesigning access to social benefits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>The Government We Need</name></author><summary type="html">The Government We Need talks with Amanda Renteria about getting public benefits to people in the digital age.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How government can make public budgeting more participatory</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-make-public-budgeting-more-participatory" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How government can make public budgeting more participatory" /><published>2020-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-make-public-budgeting-more-participatory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-make-public-budgeting-more-participatory">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.participatorybudgeting.org/what-is-pb/&quot;&gt;Participatory budgeting&lt;/a&gt; is a process that empowers community members to help decide how to spend part of a public budget. PB started in Brazil in 1989, and has since spread to more than 7,000 cities around the world. It has been used to decide budgets from states, counties, cities, housing authorities, schools, and other institutions. The New York Times calls PB “revolutionary civics in action.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode, we talk with Participatory Budgeting Project Executive Director &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/shari-davis/&quot;&gt;Shari Davis&lt;/a&gt;. PBP is a nonprofit organization advancing participatory budgeting across the United States and Canada. It has helped more than 400,000 people directly decide how to spend $300 million in public funds in 29 cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shari joined PBP after nearly 15 years of service and leadership in local government, including serving as Director of Youth Engagement and Employment for the City of Boston, where she launched Youth Lead the Change, the first youth PB process in the United States, which won the United States Conference of Mayors City Livability Award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shari talks with of &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegovweneed.com&quot;&gt;The Government We Need&lt;/a&gt; about how government can make public budgeting more participatory and, as PBP says, give people real power over real money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;call-to-action&quot;&gt;Call to action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.participatorybudgeting.org/what-is-pb/&quot;&gt;Participatory budgeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/shari_davis_what_if_you_could_help_decide_how_the_government_spends_public_funds&quot;&gt;What if you could help decide how the government spends public funds in your community?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch: &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/162743651&quot;&gt;Real Money, Real Power: Participatory Budgeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.participatorybudgeting.org/&quot;&gt;Participatory Budgeting Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/shari-davis/&quot;&gt;Shari Davis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>The Government We Need</name></author><summary type="html">Shari Davis talks with The Government We Need about building a more inclusive, democratic public budgeting process.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How government can support climate action</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-support-climate-action" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How government can support climate action" /><published>2020-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-support-climate-action</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-support-climate-action">&lt;p&gt;Sustainability is a top priority for environmentally-conscious global leaders, and it’s an issue that we’re all faced with on a daily basis, but what role should local government play in mitigating the climate crisis?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode, we talk with environmentalist and local government leader Rick Cole. Rick served as city manager of Santa Monica from 2015 to 2020, where he spearheaded ambitious initiatives on climate, homelessness, mobility, and the wellbeing of all residents. Prior to Santa Monica, Rick served as deputy mayor for Budget and Innovation for the City of Los Angeles, where he was responsible for a budget of $8.6 billion and oversaw five city departments. Rick also spent 15 years as city manager of two Southern California cities: Ventura and Azusa. He has been recognized as one of “America’s Public Officials of the Year” by Governing Magazine and one of the “Top 25 Doers, Dreamers and Drivers” by Government Technology Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rick talks with the Government We Need about creating a climate-conscious city – from policy to business and organizational collaboration – and how local governments can foster a more sustainable planet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>The Government We Need</name></author><summary type="html">The Government We Need talks with Rick Cole about local government's role in sustainability.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How government can find its purpose</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-find-its-purpose" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How government can find its purpose" /><published>2019-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-find-its-purpose</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-find-its-purpose">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, government works on the wrong problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By identifying the right problems to work on — and solving these with a performance and purpose-based mindset — government can better serve its true mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Peak Performance” author Brian Elms thinks government should be constantly asking itself questions like, “Should we be doing this at all? Are we the ones that should be doing it? If not, can we stop doing it? Can we figure out a way to get better at all these things?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Denver Mayor Michael Hancock said he wanted train city employees how to spot and fix inefficiencies in their work, Brian is the person he asked to do it. The training operation he built, called Peak Academy, quickly became a fixture in Denver City Hall — it’s trained about 7,000 employees in seven years, and saved the city close to $30 million by identifying and eliminating wasteful work in the daily lives of government employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initiative was so successful that other cities, states, and counties began adopting the model, and many have even made “Peak Performance” required reading. Brian now works with the Change and Innovation Agency, leading innovation academies all over the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian talks with The Government We Need about how government can ask the right questions and, by doing so, find its true public service purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;related&quot;&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Peak-Performance-Denvers-Boosting-Changing/dp/0983373353&quot;&gt;Peak Performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>The Government We Need</name></author><summary type="html">The Government We Need talks with Brian Elms about how government can ask the right questions and find its true public service purpose.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How we can code a better government</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-we-can-code-a-better-government" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How we can code a better government" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/episode/how-we-can-code-a-better-government</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-we-can-code-a-better-government">&lt;p&gt;Government has historically been challenged in effectively leveraging technology to best serve the people. There are numerous, well-documented cases of public sector mishandling of technology projects, from the very public failed launch of Healthcare.gov to the many unseen, ineffective IT implementations that occur on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decade ago, a movement of civic hackers — technologists working for good — inside and outside government began to eschew the trappings of Silicon Valley technology culture, instead putting their talents to use to code a better civil society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, Jen Pahlka started Code for America, a nonprofit dedicated to bringing a delivery-driven, digital mindset to government. Jen also served as deputy chief technology officer in the Obama Administration and played an instrumental role in the creation of the federal government’s U.S. Digital Service, whose mission it is “to deliver better government services to the American people through technology and design.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jen talks with The Government We Need about how we all can code a better government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;related&quot;&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://codeforamerica.org&quot;&gt;Code for America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>The Government We Need</name></author><summary type="html">The Government We Need talks with Code for America founder Jen Pahlka about how technology can be a force for civic change.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How we can bring more diversity into elected office</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-we-can-bring-more-diversity-into-elected-office" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How we can bring more diversity into elected office" /><published>2019-07-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/episode/how-we-can-bring-more-diversity-into-elected-office</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-we-can-bring-more-diversity-into-elected-office">&lt;p&gt;Starting in 2017, a wave of new political candidates began pursuing elected office at all levels of government. Many of them have been historically underrepresented in public leadership. With the support of organizations like Run for Something, fresh faces are getting elected to serve the communities and causes they care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode of The Government We Need, we talk with Sarah Horvitz, National Political Director of Run for Something. Sarah ran for an elected position on her local school board while she was still a high school student, and she won! She became passionate about ensuring that our public institutions are reflective of the people they govern, and went on to support several political races in California. She served as the Deputy Organizing Director for Hillary Clinton’s Virginia team, along with working for her campaign in the Iowa caucuses and 3 state primaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does diversity in government look like, and what impact can it have on society? How can younger candidates find opportunities to run and get elected into public office? Who are the successful candidates that have gone on to serve their communities and pave the way for a more diverse and inclusive government?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We explore these questions and more in this episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;related&quot;&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://runforsomething.net/&quot;&gt;Run for Something&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://runforsomething.net/book/&quot;&gt;Run for Something: A Real-Talk Guide to Fixing the System Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wthh.dataforprogress.org/something-to-run-for/?source=post_page---------------------------&quot;&gt;Something to Run for: Candidate Emergence in the Progressive Movement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/81080637&quot;&gt;Knock Down The House&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>The Government We Need</name></author><summary type="html">The Government We Need talks with Run for Something’s Sarah Horvitz about the changing face of local politics and how to elect diverse representation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How government can secure us in the internet+ era</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-secure-us-in-the-internet-era" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How government can secure us in the internet+ era" /><published>2019-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-secure-us-in-the-internet-era</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/episode/how-government-can-secure-us-in-the-internet-era">&lt;p&gt;The internet was not originally designed with security in mind. In the early days, this was OK, but today the landscape is more complicated because, in the internet+ era, nearly everything is connected to the internet. A spreadsheet crashes, and you lose your data. A heart device crashes, and you lose your life. Both are computers, maybe connected to the same CPU or operating system. The only difference is that the computers are attached to different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this episode of The Government We Need, we interview Bruce Schneier, an American cryptographer, computer security professional, privacy specialist and writer. Bruce is a fellow at the Berkman Center for Internet &amp;amp; Society at Harvard University and a lecturer at the Harvard Kennedy School of Government. His influential newsletter “Crypto-Gram” and his blog “Schneier on Security” are read by over 250,000 people. He is the author of over one dozen books — including his latest, Click Here to Kill Everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government has a duty of care that private companies do not. The free market doesn’t reward safety and security, so the government must step in. The government regulates stuff that kills people, and now the internet is one of those things, so the question is what does the government need to do to effectively regulate the internet+ world and keep us safe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;related&quot;&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schneier.com/books/click_here/&quot;&gt;Click Here to Kill Everybody: Security and Survival in a Hyper-connected World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GkJCI3_jbtg&quot;&gt;Bruce Schneier Click Here to Kill Everybody Talks at Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>The Government We Need</name></author><summary type="html">The Government We Need talks with Bruce Schneier about internet+ security and government’s role in keeping us safe.</summary></entry></feed>